musicstack.com 2019-03-23

# MusicStack - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**   
We are committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and using your information responsibly. 

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices of MusicStack, LLC. (sometimes referred to in this Privacy Policy as "MusicStack", "MusicStack.com", "our site", "we", or "us"), in connection with the MusicStack.com website (the "Website") and any features and online services provided by MusicStack that post or include a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Services"). We have provided this statement of our Privacy Policy to answer your questions about the types of information that we gather, the ways in which we use and share this information, and your rights and choices regarding such information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By visiting and using the Services, you agree that your use of the Services is governed by this Privacy Policy. In addition to our Privacy Policy, your use of the Services is governed by our Terms of Use, which govern in the event of any conflict with this Privacy Policy. 

**SCOPE OF PRIVACY POLICY**  
This Privacy Policy applies to the MusicStack.com website and any features and online services provided by MusicStack that post or include a link to this Privacy Policy. It does not apply to MusicStack's services that MusicStack's customers may use on their own websites, to other companies' or organizations' sites to which we link, or to companies that MusicStack does not own or control, even if such companies are contractors or business partners of MusicStack. 

This Privacy Policy also does not cover how MusicStack customers may treat your information as the use of your information by such parties is governed by the privacy policies of such parties and is not subject to MusicStack's control. If you are a data subject located in Europe, please see the section below entitled "Data Controller" for more information on our relationship with our customers. 

**Third Party Content and Links To Third Party Sites**  
Our site may contain content that is supplied by a third party, and those third parties may collect Site usage information when you browse web pages from our site or content served to your browser. In addition, when you are on Our Site you may be directed to other web sites that are operated and controlled by third parties that we do not control. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any of these third parties or third party web sites. For example, if you click on a banner advertisement, the click may take you off our site onto a different web site. These other web sites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. We encourage you to note when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of all third party web sites before submitting any personal information to those sites. 

**INFORMATION MUSICSTACK COLLECTS**  
  
**Information You Provide**  
We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us while using the Services, such as when you register an account, make a purchase of one of the products listed on our site, or communicate with our customer service team or with other users of the Services. 

The information we collect includes information relating to identified or identifiable natural persons. Some examples of information we collect include the following: contact data, including your first and last name, telephone number, email address, and postal address; and billing information; credentials, including your passwords; content data, including the content of the messages you send to us. We also use third party payment processes to collect and process payment data, including your payment instrument and security code associated with your payment instrument, on our behalf. 

You may choose to voluntarily submit other information to us through the Services that we do not request, and, in such instances, you are solely responsible for such information. 

Our site permits you to submit photographs and images, image URLs, user profiles, writings, music, audio, video, questions, comments or other content, which may include personal information. We or others may reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use this content in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed). Others may have access to this content and may have the ability to share it with third parties. Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including personal information, in connection with your personal content. Please note that we do not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you disclose publicly, share with others or otherwise upload onto our site. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any content or information that you disclose or receive through our site. For the full terms and conditions regarding personal content you submit to our site, please review our [Terms of Use](https://www.musicstack.com/terms.cgi). 

**Information Collected Automatically**  
We automatically collect information about your device and how your device interacts with our Service. The types of data we collect and the methods by which we may collect such data include the following: 

**Web Beacons**  
MusicStack may also use web beacons, small graphic images or other web programming code (also known as "1x1 GIFs" or "clear GIFs"), which may be included in our web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Services, to monitor how users navigate the Services, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed. 

**Embedded Scripts**  
MusicStack may also use embedded scripts in connection with the provision of its Services. "Embedded scripts" are programming code designed to collect information about your interactions with a website, such as the links you click on, and may assist our customers in providing us with information used to provide the Services. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server, our customer's web server, or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the website containing the embedded script, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter. 

**Log File Information**  
Your web browser automatically sends information to every website you visit, including ours. For example, our server logs may receive and record information such as the pages you access on the Services, referring URLs, your browser type, your operating system, the date and time of your visit, and the duration of your visit to each page. 

**User Agent Strings**  
Log file information may also include a user agent string, a series of characters automatically sent with your Internet requests that provide information necessary for smooth Internet communications, such as the operating system and browser you used. A user agent string might be used to identify the device originating a message. 

**Location Data**  
MusicStack may also request access to or otherwise receive information about your device location when you access the Services. Your location data may be based on your IP address and other location-aware technologies. We use location data in connection with providing the Services and to help improve the Services. 

**Image and Audio Data**  
If you upload an image or audio, or provide a URL that points to an image or audio file MusicStack may transfer that data (or data the resides at the URL) to our servers or to the account that MusicStack controls on Amazon AWS for hosting and providing of Services. 

**Cookies**  
This site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This section describes what information the cookies gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or 'break' certain elements of the sites functionality.

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser. They make it possible for us to recognize your browser when you visit. By doing this, we can personalize your return visits. For example cookies save you time during checkout by not requiring you to sign in again, or by remember your currency preference so prices are displayed in a currency you are familiar with. In order to enjoy such benefits, your browser must be set to accept cookies. 

For more information on cookies visit <https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie> and <https://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. 

**How We Use Cookies**  
We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not. This will ensure that our website will work as intended and provide you the best user experience possible.

**The Cookies We Set**  

  * Account related cookies

If you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.

  * Login related cookies

We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.

  * Forms related cookies

When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.

  * Site preferences cookies

In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences. Examples of of these cookies set could be to remember your prefered currency or recent last searches you performed on the site.

**Third Party Cookies**  
In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. This section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official [Google Analytics page](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). 

  * We also use third party advertisements on MusicStack to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program, or other advertisers that advertise via [Freestar.io](https://freestar.io/), information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited or your interests. 

If you would prefer not to receive interest based advertising you can [opt out here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

  * Third party cookies are also used by MusicStack partners (such as ShieldSquare.com) for Bot detection. These bot detection cookies collects information regarding the device used to access MusicStack, including IP address and device identifying information. We use these cookies and the information they collect for web-traffic filtration and fraud prevention purposes. 
  * We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; Facebook, Twitter, Google and Instagram, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

**HOW MUSICSTACK USES INFORMATION**   
We use information for our legitimate interests, including for the following purposes: 

**Providing Our Services**  
MusicStack uses information such as images or image URLs that you provide, your first and last name, telephone number, email address, postal address, billing information, or other contact information we obtain from you, our customers, or our business partners, for the purposes of helping you buy and sell your products and other services. 

**Communications with You**  
MusicStack maintains one or more contact lists (with email addresses and other information) to allow MusicStack to communicate with individuals who do business with MusicStack or who have expressed an interest in the Services. We may contact you to confirm your purchases, give order updates, or respond to requests that you make, notify you of changes to your account or the Services, for marketing purposes, or to otherwise inform you of information related to our business or your account with us. 

**Website Administration and Customization**  
MusicStack uses the information we collect about you for a variety of website administration and customization purposes. For example, we use your information to process your registration request, provide you with services and communications that you have requested, send you email updates and other communications, customize features and advertising that appear on and off the Services, deliver the Services content to you, measure Services traffic, measure user interests and traffic patterns, and improve the Services. 

**Usage of IP Addresses**  
The MusicStack services, or third parties services that MusicStack partners with (such as ShieldSquare.com), use IP addresses to help detect and block robotic and/or fraudulent activity or to deterimine your general geographic location. 

**Consent**  
We also use information with your consent, including for the following purposes: to allow you to participate in our surveys; to serve advertising tailored to your interests on our Services and third party services; and to fulfill any other purpose disclosed to you and with your consent. Some of our lawful bases for processing your information stem from our customers on whose behalf we provide services. MusicStack uses information that does not identify you for any purpose except as prohibited by applicable law. For information on your rights and choices regarding how we use your information, please see the below section titled "Your Rights and Choices". 

**HOW MUSICSTACK SHARES INFORMATION**

**Sharing with Our Service Providers**  
We provide your information to our third party service providers, contractors, business partners, and advertisers, for the purpose of delivering services to you as well as for purposes related to Services administration and operation, including conducting analytics and rooting out fraud and robots. When sharing information for the purpose of providing you with the services you request, we will share your information only as necessary for the third party working on MusicStack's behalf to complete its work for us. 

We may use anonymous, statistical or aggregated information about the website's use and share, publish, post, disseminate, transmit or otherwise communicate or make available such information, to suppliers, controllers, business partners, sponsors, affiliates and any other third party, at our sole discretion. 

**Customers**  
We share your information with our customers in connection with us processing your information on their behalf. For example, we share your information with our customers to respond to your questions and comments, fulfill your order requests, deterime fraud risk, and otherwise comply with applicable law. 

**Third Parties**  
We may share your information with third parties for purposes of providing you with tailored advertisements, measuring and improving our Service and advertising effectiveness, detecting fraud, and enabling other enhancements. 

**Security and Compliance with the Law**  
We reserve the right to disclose your information to appropriate third parties if we are required to do so by law or we believe that such action is necessary in order (a) to comply with a legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order; (b) to protect the company's rights and property; (c) to investigate reports of users sending material using a false email address or users sending harassing, threatening, or abusive messages; (d) to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Website or Services; or (e) to respond to emergencies, such as when we believe someone's physical safety is at risk. MusicStack may be required to disclose information in a life-threatening emergency or in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

**Transfer of Business**  
In the event that we sell some or all of our assets, or our company is acquired by another company, or during the negotiation of such sale or acquisition, our databases and any information we collect may be among the transferred or negotiated assets. 

**Consent**  
We may share your information for any other purpose disclosed to you and with your consent. 

Without limiting the foregoing, in our sole discretion, MusicStack shares information that does not identify you with third parties, including our customers, for any purpose except as prohibited by applicable law. For information on your rights and choices regarding how we share your information, please see the section below titled "Your Rights and Choices". 

**THIRD PARTY ANALYTICS; ONLINE TRACKING**  
MusicStack works with certain third parties (including analytics companies) to provide us with information regarding traffic on and use of the Services. Some of these parties collect information when you visit the Services or other online websites and services. These third parties set and access their own tracking technologies (including cookies, embedded scripts, and web beacons) and may otherwise collect or have access to your IP address or other unique identifier, log information, and related information about you. These tracking technologies, including the Google Analytics User ID feature, may be used to assist in providing analytics, marketing, and for other purposes. We also use third party plug-ins from ShieldSquare to protect our services from robots and fraudulent users. ShieldSqaure's privacy policy is available at https://www.shieldsquare.com/privacy/. MusicStack does not control the information collection, use, or sharing practices of such third party providers, and we encourage you to consult their online policies. Some third parties may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use the Services. 

**YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES**  
**Opt-Out of Email Communications**  
If you are a registered member of the Services, you can make changes to your account information by logging into the Website and modifying your preferences. If you do not wish to receive email notifications from us, you may opt-out by contacting us with your request. In addition, certain email communications we send to you, such as newsletters and promotional announcements, contain a clearly worded "Opt-Out" or "Unsubscribe" link allowing you to withdraw your permission for future mailings. Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the Services (for example, administrative, service announcements or updates on your order purchases) and these transactional account messages may be unaffected even if you opt-out from marketing communications. 

**Blocking or Deleting Cookies**  
You can manually delete cookies, which are normally located in your temporary Internet folder or cookie folder. You can also reset the preferences in your web browser to notify you when you have received a cookie or, alternatively, to refuse to accept cookies. Deleting or blocking cookies will prohibit your ability to make online purchases on the Services and to use and access portions of the Services that require logging in with a username and password, and may affect other functionality. 

**Analytics and Advertising**  
You may exercise choice regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> and downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. 

For more information about and to exercise certain choices regarding interest based ads from ad networks, go to:

U.S.: <https://www.aboutads.info/choices> and <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.  
European Union: [https://www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)  
Canada: <https://youradchoices.ca/>

Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of interest-based advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads. Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain interest-based advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). MusicStack is not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties' opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs. 

Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a "Do Not Track" signal to websites and online services you visit; however, there is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Like many websites and online services, the Website currently does not alter its practices when it receives a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," you may wish to visit [https://www.allaboutdnt.com](https://www.allaboutdnt.com/). 

**Retention of Personal Information**  
We retain personal information we process for as long as an account is active or as needed to provide the Services. If you wish to terminate your account or request that we no longer use your data, please contact us using the information found in the "CONTACT FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION, OPTING OUT, DATA ACCESS AND CORRECTION, AND DISPUTES" section below. We will retain your data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate financial and other records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will delete all your data within 30 days once you raise the request to us except as otherwise prohibited by applicable law. 

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
California's "Shine the Light" law permits customers in California to request certain details about how a business shares their personal information as defined by "Shine the Light" with third parties (and in some cases affiliates) for those third parties' or affiliates' own direct marketing purposes. 

MusicStack does not share personal information as defined under California's "Shine the Light" law with third parties or affiliates for those third parties' or affiliates' direct marketing purposes. California customers may request information about our compliance with this law by contacting us. Any such inquiry must include "California Privacy Rights Request" in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email or mail address. 

**European Privacy Rights**  
If you are a data subject in Europe, you have the right to access, rectify, or erase any personal data we have collected about you through the Services. You also have the right to data portability and the right to restrict or object to our processing of personal data we have collected about you through the Services. In addition, you have the right to ask us not to process your personal data (or provide it to third parties to process) for marketing purposes or purposes materially different than for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. You may withdraw your consent at any time for any data processing we do based on consent you have provided to us. 

To exercise any of these rights, contact us using the information below in the "CONTACT FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION, OPTING OUT, DATA ACCESS AND CORRECTION, AND DISPUTES" section and specify which right you intend to exercise. We will respond to your request within 30 days. We may require additional information from you to allow us to confirm your identity. Please note that we store information as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, and may continue to retain and use the information even after a data subject request for purposes of our legitimate interests, including as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent fraud, and enforce our agreements. 

If your information has been processed by us on behalf of one of our customers and you wish to exercise any rights you have with such information, please inquire with our customer directly. If you wish to make your request directly to MusicStack, please provide the name of the MusicStack customer on whose behalf MusicStack processes your information. We will refer your request to that customer, and will support them to the extent required by applicable law in responding to your request. 

If you have any issues with our compliance, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a European supervisory authority. 

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER AND PRIVACY SHIELD**  
We are based in the U.S. and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. If you are accessing the Services from outside of the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the Services may be transferred to, processed, stored, and used in the U.S. and other jurisdictions. Data protection laws in the U.S. and other jurisdictions may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Services or provision of any information therefore constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your information in the U.S. and other jurisdictions as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If your data is collected in Europe, we will transfer your personal data subject to appropriate or suitable safeguards, such as the Privacy Shield Framework discussed below. 

MusicStack complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. MusicStack adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. 

MusicStack is subject to the investigatory and enforcement jurisdiction of the United States Federal Trade Commission in complying with its commitments under the Privacy Shield Principles. We hereby affirm our commitment to subject to the Privacy Shield Principles all personal data transferred from the European Union and Switzerland in reliance on Privacy Shield. This means that MusicStack shall be liable to you for any third party agent to which we transfer your personal data and that processes such personal data in a manner that violates the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we can demonstrate that we are not responsible for the resulting damages. MusicStack takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is relevant to its intended use and is accurate, complete, and current and retained only as long as needed for an intended or compatible purpose. 

Any inquiries or complaints relating to MusicStack's compliance with Privacy Shield, including any requests for access or correction of personal data, may be addressed to our Data Protection Officer set forth in this Privacy Policy. MusicStack will investigate and attempt to resolve any inquiries brought to its attention. MusicStack commits to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint. Under limited circumstances, in the event your complaint is not resolved through these channels a binding arbitration option may be available for a Privacy Shield Panel. 

If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/. 

**SECURITY**  
MusicStack implements reasonable administrative, physical, and technical security measures to help protect your data from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. However, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable. MusicStack cannot guarantee the security of the Service's servers or databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. 

**POLICY REGARDING CHILDREN**  
The Services are not intended for use by minor children without the supervison of a responsible adult. MusicStack does not knowingly collect information from minor children. If you are a parent or guardian, and believe we have collected information about your child in violation of this policy, please contact us. 

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy in response to changing business circumstances and legal developments. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how we are collecting and using your information. 

**DATA CONTROLLER**  
EU data protection law makes a distinction between organizations that process personal data for their own purposes (known as "controllers") and organizations that process personal data on behalf of other organizations (known as "processors"). 

MusicStack, located at the address set forth below, generally operates as a processor on behalf of its customers that use the MusicStack's services. The MusicStack customer, the controller, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data, such as orders that come to them through our Services. MusicStack's customer decides what personal data to share on our Services. Please visit the applicable customer's privacy policy for information about their privacy practices. 

MusicStack also operates as a controller with respect to certain of its services. For example, MusicStack operates as a controller in connection with personal data collected from visitors through its website. Also, when MusicStack combines personal data from different customers, like many kinds of analytics services or orders of customers, it may do this both as a processor at its customers' instruction and as a controller itself for the purpose of providing services to all of its customers. For example, MusicStack may process and aggregate some of the personal data that a customer shares with MusicStack in order to make that personal data part of another database for one or more other services provided to MusicStack customers. 

If you are a data subject located in Europe and want to learn more about how to exercise your rights, please see the section above entitled "European Privacy Rights". 

**CONTACT FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION, OPTING OUT, DATA ACCESS AND CORRECTION, AND DISPUTES**  
If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy, or you wish to exercise your opt-out rights hereunder or access or correct data applicable to you, please contact us: 

By email: legal@musicstack.com

By mail:

Dave Stack (Privacy Agent)  
MusicStack LLC  
2920 Jay Ave  
Cleveland, OH 44113 

For EU-specific requests, including our compliance with Privacy Shield, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: 

By email: dpo@musicstack.com

By mail: 

Data Protection Officer  
MusicStack LLC  
2920 Jay Ave  
Cleveland, OH 44113 

_Last Updated: 11/13/2018_
